Brandon Loveall

Full Stack Developer - Salt Lake City - <u>bloveall02@gmail.com</u> - <u>Portfolio</u> - <u>Github</u> - <u>LinkedIn</u>

Summary

Highly motivated software developer with excellent leadership skills and requires little supervision to produce excellent results. Strong knowledge of modern frameworks and languages and excels in a team setting. Currently searching for an environment that will challenge my proven skill set while allowing me to develop new skills.

<u>Skills</u>					
Javascript	Node.js	Express.js	HTML5/CSS3	Python	Git/Github
AWS	Typescript	PostgreSQL/SQL	Angular	React/Redux	Unix/Linux

Projects

Conway's Game of Life 9/2022, Personal | Demo | Github

React | HTML5/CSS3 | JavsScript

Stylistically simple showcase of the cell simulation "Conway's Game of Life". Visitors are able to place down, clear, and customize the cell grid, in which cells will "simulate" different actions based off a set of rules.

- Implemented a lazy loading algorithm to ensure fast performance between grid rerenders.
- Created a customizable cell grid with optimized code to minimize rerenders
- Rewrote simulation code to guarantee readability for future updates

Chirper Social Media Site 9/2022, Devmountain | Demo | Github

React | HTML5/CSS3 | JavsScript | PostgreSQL | Express.js | Node.js

Fully functional social media website where users can create an account, make posts, search for and view other profiles, and customize their profile.

- Utilized React to break up the website into 15 modular components
- Implemented a responsive design using CSS for a clean user experience across multiple devices
- Built with practical development principles to maintain functional and readable code

Country API Front End 8/2022, Personal | Demo | Github

React | HTML5/CSS3 | JavaScript

Responsive front end display for the REST Countries API in which users are able to query for information on different countries with filters or a search bar.

- Devised an efficient layout for the site given pre-built images of the requested final website
- Improved the loading speed of countries by minimizing API requests and caching results
- Accurately created the final, functional website while only being given images and concept functionality of the requested final product

News Website 7/2022, Devmountain | Demo | Github

HTML5/CSS3 | JavsScript | PostgreSQL | Express.js | Node.js

Mock news website where users are able to submit articles and read articles from other users.

- Amplified the user experience by keeping the site layout to a minimum number of elements
- Formed a fully functional front end and back end with clean coding principles
- Revamped the overall design by utilizing flexbox in multiple areas for simple scaling

Development Experience

Full Stack Developer 07/2020-Present

Began software development as a teenager with passion to learn all there is in this vast and diverse field. Software development remains a strong presence in my life.

- Studying and working with programming languages for 6+ years.
- Working with modern software development frameworks and technologies for 2 years.
- Building and creating new applications while utilizing all facets of software development to continue building expertise.

Work Experience

Learning Assistant 01/2022-06/2022, Salt Lake Community College

Mentorship role within the Mathematics section of Salt Lake Community College as an in-class tutor.

- Supported 24 college students with their college algebra and calculus coursework
- Designed a form system for students to set up personal tutoring sessions without schedule conflict
- Collaborated with fellow learning assistants to invent new methods of teaching our students

Mathematics Tutor 09/2021-01/2022, Mathnasium

- Mathematics tutor for 50+ students, with coursework including college level algebra and calculus
- Invented unique problem solving methods to help students tackle challenging problems
- Multitasked between tutoring up to 5 students at a time without a decrease in quality of teaching

Education

Full Stack Development 05/2022 - 09/2022, Devmountain

Associate of Science 2020-2022, Salt Lake Community College

GPA 3.7

Member of PTK honor society, awarded the New Century Pathway Transfer Scholarship for academic excellence and service to the community in 2022 (website)